<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on Chmouel's blog</title><link>https://blog.chmouel.com/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on Chmouel's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-GB</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 11:24:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chmouel.com/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building RPM with Docker images</title><link>https://blog.chmouel.com/2014/12/31/building-rpm-with-docker-images/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 11:24:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmouel.com/2014/12/31/building-rpm-with-docker-images/</guid><description>For an internal project at work I have been thinking about more how to generate RPMs out of our CI. I wanted to have them produced as artifacts of the build so I can test how if they can be installed and properly working with some smoketests.
Since we are using Docker for most of the things in our CI, I have been thinking about more about how to do that with docker images and RPM.</description></item><item><title>Howto use backtrack4 from hard disk with Grub2</title><link>https://blog.chmouel.com/2010/03/08/howto-use-backtrack4-from-hard-disk-with-grub2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 12:00:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmouel.com/2010/03/08/howto-use-backtrack4-from-hard-disk-with-grub2/</guid><description>If you want to boot backtrack4 from time to time on your Linux desktop/laptop but don&amp;rsquo;t want to carry it on a USB drive (or CDROM) on you then this guide may help.
I am using Debian unstable on my laptop but I am sure you can adapt it to anything you want. I am using another partition (/dev/sda6) as my backtrack partition but it&amp;rsquo;s possible to copy the full thing in / as well on your main partition.</description></item><item><title>XMPP notification for irssi running in a screen on a remote host</title><link>https://blog.chmouel.com/2009/12/20/xmpp-notification-for-irssi-running-in-a-screen-on-a-remote-host/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2009 15:41:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmouel.com/2009/12/20/xmpp-notification-for-irssi-running-in-a-screen-on-a-remote-host/</guid><description>Like a lot of people I have my irssi on a server in a screen. This has
been working great so far but my only concerns are the notifications
on the desktop when something happening.
Over the time I have found some different solution with mitigated
results for me :
Use fanotify script with the libnotify-bin and SSH like mentioned here.
Setup your irssi (or other) as irc proxy bouncer and connect with</description></item><item><title>Vmware vmplayer and kernel 2.6.32</title><link>https://blog.chmouel.com/2009/12/05/vmware-vmplayer-and-kernel-2-6-32/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2009 01:35:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmouel.com/2009/12/05/vmware-vmplayer-and-kernel-2-6-32/</guid><description>So you have a shiny new linux-2.6.32 kernel installed but your VMPlayer does not work anymore since the vmnet module does not compile by throwing this error :
CC [M] /tmp/vmware-root/modules/vmnet-only/vnetEvent.o
CC [M] /tmp/vmware-root/modules/vmnet-only/vnetUserListener.o
/tmp/vmware-root/modules/vmnet-only/vnetUserListener.c: In function ‘VNetUserListenerEventHandler’:
/tmp/vmware-root/modules/vmnet-only/vnetUserListener.c:240: error: ‘TASK_INTERRUPTIBLE’ undeclared (first use in this function)
/tmp/vmware-root/modules/vmnet-only/vnetUserListener.c:240: error: (Each undeclared identifier is reported only once
/tmp/vmware-root/modules/vmnet-only/vnetUserListener.c:240: error: for each function it appears in.)
/tmp/vmware-root/modules/vmnet-only/vnetUserListener.c: In function ‘VNetUserListenerRead’:
/tmp/vmware-root/modules/vmnet-only/vnetUserListener.c:282: error: ‘TASK_INTERRUPTIBLE’ undeclared (first use in this function)</description></item><item><title>Toshiba Regza 32AV615DB blank screen HDMI Linux</title><link>https://blog.chmouel.com/2009/12/03/toshiba-regza-32av615db-blank-screen-hdmi-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2009 17:17:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmouel.com/2009/12/03/toshiba-regza-32av615db-blank-screen-hdmi-linux/</guid><description>I have this nice Toshiba TV which is connected to a small Linux box which act as a media player. I have been some issue lately the things works fine under the 1920x1800 resolution most of the time. But once in a while I get a blank screen and the nvidia driver telling me this :
(II) Dec 03 17:00:19 NVIDIA(0): &amp;ldquo;nvidia-auto-select&amp;rdquo;
(II) Dec 03 17:00:19 NVIDIA(0): Virtual screen size determined to be 640 x 480</description></item><item><title>Nokia N95 bluetooth teethering with T-Mobile under Linux and Delll Latitude D630</title><link>https://blog.chmouel.com/2009/10/30/nokia-n95-bluetooth-teethering-with-t-mobile-under-linux-and-delll-latitude-d630/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 08:55:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmouel.com/2009/10/30/nokia-n95-bluetooth-teethering-with-t-mobile-under-linux-and-delll-latitude-d630/</guid><description>Spent a bit of time to configure my Nokia mobile to teethering wih my Linux and T-Mobile. Here is some steps that may help the others :
If you don&amp;rsquo;t have that blue bluetooth led switched on on your Dell Latitude D630 Laptop you have to enable it. I haven&amp;rsquo;t find any way to do that via the Linux Kernel module but with Windows under Vmware Player (3.0) enabling Bluetooth and installing the driver (manually not via the setup.</description></item></channel></rss>