<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on Chmouel&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.chmouel.com/categories/uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on Chmouel&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 08:55:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chmouel.com/categories/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tekton yaml templates and script feature</title>
      <link>https://blog.chmouel.com/2020/07/28/tekton-yaml-templates-and-script-feature/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 08:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chmouel.com/2020/07/28/tekton-yaml-templates-and-script-feature/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t you love &amp;ldquo;yaml&amp;rdquo;, yes you do ! or at least that&amp;rsquo;s what the industry told you to love!
When you were in school your teacher told you about &amp;ldquo;XML&amp;rdquo; and how it will solve all the industry problems (and there was many in the late 90s). But you learned that you hate reaching to your &amp;quot;&amp;lt;&amp;quot; and&amp;quot; &amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;quot; keys and rather have something else. So then the industry came up with &amp;ldquo;json&amp;rdquo; so computer or yourself can talk to each others, that&amp;rsquo;s nice for computers but actually not so nice for yourself it was actually a lie and was not made for yourself to read and write but only for comptures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving on from Rackspace and joining eNovance.</title>
      <link>https://blog.chmouel.com/2012/12/12/moving-on-from-rackspace-and-joining-enovance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 06:24:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chmouel.com/2012/12/12/moving-on-from-rackspace-and-joining-enovance/</guid>
      <description>After almost five years at Rackspace UK I have now decided to move on and come back for good to Paris I will be now at eNovance working as before on OpenStack projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging python-novaclient on the command line.</title>
      <link>https://blog.chmouel.com/2011/09/02/debugging-python-novaclient-on-the-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 03:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chmouel.com/2011/09/02/debugging-python-novaclient-on-the-command-line/</guid>
      <description>I have done lately quite a bit of work with python-novaclientthe (nova/keystone) openstack client. I often experiment it with ipythonin the console.
There is a nice debugging facility in novaclient which you can see while using &amp;ndash;debug argument on the command line and if you wanted to use it with ipython you could have that at the beginning of your session :
This would give you the details of the session showing you the REST requests and responses including the headers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
